# Nikolai Dorofeev

## System Analyst

IT specialist of experience in wide range of technologies. Worked with different ecosystems: JavaScript, Node.js, Python, Java, C#. Integrated systems via REST API, SOAP, gRPC, RabbitMQ. Took lead role in creation of documentation for Kubernetes-based microservices solution.



### Languages

- English: Upper-Intermediate
- · Russian: Native

#### Skills

UML



Microservices

Design patterns

## Work Experience

Full-stack Developer Exactpro (Georgia)

Jul 2022 - Present (1 year 1 month)

- Led development of an easy-to-deploy and easy-to-update docs web toolkit package based on Nuxt.js and Tailwind CSS
- Developed #1 architecture for providing traceability of digital assets between Blockchains for Swift Hackathon 2022
- Mentored junior specialists and technical writers

#### Full-stack Developer Exactpro

Jul 2021 - Jul 2022 (1 year 1 month)

- Developed a custom website template for documentation with features for technical writers using Gridsome (Vue.js + GraphQL)
- Developed demonstration Python and Kotlin modules for th2 complex Kubernetes-based microservices framework with gRPC and RabbitMQ communication
- Wrote clear and easy-to-understand documentation for complex Kubernetesbased microservices framework

#### Full-stack Developer (Front-end heavy) WebSphere

Feb 2018 - Apr 2021 (3 years 3 months)

- Implemented frontend architectures, utilizing Vue.js, to create scalable and modular web applications. Utilized VueX for state management.
- Ensured seamless user experiences across various devices, optimizing applications for desktops, tablets, and mobile devices.
- Leveraged Node.js and Express.js to integrate server-side APIs, enabling seamless communication between the frontend and backend systems.
- Collaborated closely with UI/UX designers to transform wireframes into user-friendly interfaces.
- Conducted thorough testing and debugging to ensure cross-browser compatibility and a consistent user experience across different web browsers

## **Projects**

- <u>tradeb0t</u>: in Trading software with high integration possibilities
- <u>th2-cli</u>: 🧖 CLI for managing th2 infrastructure in Kubernetes cluster
- <u>tweetst0rm</u>: 🐔 Simple app that uses GPT-3 for generating tweets.

## Certificates

- Enterprise Patterns (<u>foxminded.ua</u>, May 2023): Course Page, Certificate, Verify
  Certificate
- Architecting With Google Kubernetes Engine (<u>Coursera</u>, Oct 2021): Certificate
- Fundamentals Of Digital Marketing (<u>Google Digital Garage</u>, Jul 2021):
   Certificate

#### Education

Information Systems And Technologies Tomsk Polytechnic University
Sep 2018 - Jul 2022 (3 years 11 months)

Get a bachelor's degree in Information Systems and Technology in Business.